<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vanan Andreas on V's personal site</title><link>https://rezonated.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Vanan Andreas on V's personal site</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rezonated.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simulating 1000 flocking fish in Unreal Engine</title><link>https://rezonated.github.io/posts/1000_boids/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rezonated.github.io/posts/1000_boids/</guid><description>Introduction Simulating the flocking behavior of birds or the schooling of fish is a classic problem in computer graphics. The Boids algorithm, created by Craig Reynolds in 1986, offers a powerful solution. It demonstrates how complex, life-like group motion can emerge from individuals following a few simple rules, without any central leader or complex choreography.
This principle offers a way to add life to game worlds. A common application is simulating a school of fish, but a significant technical challenge arises when scaling up to large numbers.</description></item><item><title>TNonNullPtr: UE's bouncer for null pointers!</title><link>https://rezonated.github.io/posts/tnonnullptr/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rezonated.github.io/posts/tnonnullptr/</guid><description>Introduction If you&amp;rsquo;ve spent any time writing gameplay code in Unreal&amp;rsquo;s C++, you know the routine. The code we all have to write.
Before you can safely use a pointer, you have to check it. This defensive habit is essential for preventing crashes, but it often leads to code that looks like this:
1void AMyGameMode::StartRound(const AController* PlayerController) 2{ 3	if (PlayerController) 4	{ 5	if (PlayerController-&amp;gt;GetPawn&amp;lt;AMyCharacter&amp;gt;()) 6	{ 7	if (PlayerController-&amp;gt;GetPawn&amp;lt;AMyCharacter&amp;gt;()-&amp;gt;GetMyWeaponComponent()) 8	{ 9	PlayerController-&amp;gt;GetPawn&amp;lt;AMyCharacter&amp;gt;()-&amp;gt;GetMyWeaponComponent()-&amp;gt;EquipWeapon(); 10	} 11	} 12	} 13} This code is safe, perfectly fine.</description></item><item><title>Approaches to replicate Unreal Engine's TMap</title><link>https://rezonated.github.io/posts/tmap_replication/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rezonated.github.io/posts/tmap_replication/</guid><description>Introduction If you ever attempt to put a Replicated specifier on your UPROPERTY with TMap, your IDE or compiler might yell at you like this:
Why can&amp;rsquo;t TMap be replicated by Unreal? Unreal&amp;rsquo;s built-in replication only supports certain types that the replication system knows how to serialize. This includes basic primitives, some containers like TArray, FVector, or custom structs containing UPROPERTY fields.
TMap is considered a dynamic container because of its non-fixed size, ordering, and hashing behavior.</description></item><item><title>Networked Deterministic Array Shuffle in Unreal Engine</title><link>https://rezonated.github.io/posts/deterministic_shuffle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rezonated.github.io/posts/deterministic_shuffle/</guid><description>Introduction Sometimes, you want to do a deterministic shuffle of an array for purposes like gacha mechanics, or in my case, replicating the Spin the Wheel minigame in Coral Island!
At the time this feature was developed, it hadn&amp;rsquo;t yet been made to work with multiplayer. Even though Coral Island is a co-op game, not a competitive one, Unreal Engine still adopts a server-authoritative multiplayer model.
The server must always act as the single source of truth.</description></item><item><title>CV</title><link>https://rezonated.github.io/cv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rezonated.github.io/cv/</guid><description>Download</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://rezonated.github.io/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rezonated.github.io/projects/</guid><description>A list of my past and current projects:
Project Wiki
ue-restyle My fork of Restyle, an Unreal Engine 5 plugin that redesigns graph editors. My version adds compatibility for major engine updates.
Technologies:
Unreal Engine 5 C++ Slate UI GitHub repo
OpenAI Unreal A plugin that wraps OpenAI API and exposes its functionality to Unreal Engine&amp;rsquo;s Blueprint system.
Technologies:
Unreal Engine 5 C++ HTTP JSON Unreal automation suite functional tests GitHub repo</description></item><item><title>V's Personal Interview Preparation Note</title><link>https://rezonated.github.io/intv_prep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rezonated.github.io/intv_prep/</guid><description>Wow you found this page, welcome! It&amp;rsquo;s either you;
Typed the correct URL (if that&amp;rsquo;s the case, congrats!) One of people that I trust and owe something to, so I hope this can help and paid a bit of something I owed Here&amp;rsquo;s my personal interview preparation note. It started as an old note that I wrote back in college as a fresh-graduate, found in an old hard drive
But I decided to improve the whole thing by fact-checking and adding some things that either actually get asked in the interview or things that I learned, gained and experienced during my ~5 years of career thus far</description></item><item><title>Whoami</title><link>https://rezonated.github.io/whoami/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rezonated.github.io/whoami/</guid><description>Wow you found this page!
Hi again, my name is Vanan Andreas, although my full name is actually a lot longer than that ( Andreas Evananda Gusti Purwanto ) - an Indonesian programmer specializing in game development using major game engines (Unreal Engine, Unity).
I don&amp;rsquo;t have any reward for you for finding this page, but feel free to scroll through to know me a bit more!
Preferred tools Hardware PC CPU: AMD Ryzen 9 5950X GPU: GALAX NVIDIA RTX 3070 Ti Motherboard: MSI MPG X570 Gaming Plus RAM: 4x32GB DDR4 Corsair Vengeance RGB PRO PSU: MSI MPG A850GF Cooler: Deepcool LT720 360mm Storage: 2x4TB Samsung 990 PRO 4x4TB WD Blue Case: MSI MPG Gungnir 110R Laptop: ThinkPad T61 w/ Middleton BIOS CPU: Harvested Intel Core2Duo T9500 RAM: Harvested 2x4GB DDR3 OEM sticks Misc.</description></item></channel></rss>